Guide to the Roman Gulʹ Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1881-1966; Series I; 9.5; (26 boxes)
  - INCOMING
    - Klenovskii, Dmitrii, 1952-64 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Kodzhomberdiev, Kudaibergen, 1947-51, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 168-69)
    - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich, 1946-[65], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 170-73)
    - Kosbun, Ivan Aledseevich
      See: Kurganov, Ivan Alekseevich, Box 8, folder 183
    - Koshko, Ol'ga Ivanovna, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Kromiadi, K., 1952-62, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Kruglikov, Samuil Markovich, 1948-51 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Krymov, Vl. (Vladimir), 1933-58 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Ktorova, Alla, 1960-64 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Kubanskii, Fedor, 1952-62 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Kubas, Ivan, 1948, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Kucherov, Samuil L'vovich, 1953-61 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Kurganov, Ivan Alekseevich, 1949-51, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 183)
      See also: Series III, Subject Files, Pol. Organizations: RND - folder 59
    - Kuskova, Ekaterina Dmitrievna, 1946-57 (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Kuznetsova, Galina Nikolaevna, 1963-65 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - "L" general, 1936-64, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 186-90)
    - Lazarevich, Ida Markovna, 1949-51 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Levitskii, Sergei Aleksandrovich, 1954-65 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Losskii, N. O. (Nikolai Onufrievich), 1952-61 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - "M" general, 1932-65, n.d. (Box 8-9, Folder 194-201)
    - Mackiewicz, Józef, 1961-64 (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich, 1953-62 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Manuilov, Mikhail Dmitrievich, 1950-[54] (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Marchenko, Nikolai Nikolaevich
      See: Morshen, Nikolai, Box 9, folder 218
    - Marchenko, Nikolai Vladimirovich
      See: Narokov, Nikolai, Box 10, folder 223
    - Marchenko, Vasilii Pavlovich
      See: Martchenko, Basilius, Box 9, folder 209
    - Margolin, IUlii, 1947-65 (Box 9, Folder 205-07)
    - Margolina, Eva Efimovna, [1930]-64 (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - Martchenko, Basilius, 1948-52 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Matskevich, Iosif Antonovich
      See: Mackiewicz, Józef, Box 9, folder 202
    - Matskevich, Nikolai Emel'ianovich, 1952-60 (Box 9, Folder 210-211)
    - Mel'gunov, S. P. (Sergei Petrovich), 1946-49, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 212-214)
      See also: Series III, Subject Files. Miscellany. "Cases", Box 58, folder 1503
    - Merinov, Dimitrii V., 1945-63, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 215)
    - Mikhalevskii, Pavel Mikhailovich, 1949-50 (Box 9, Folder 216)
    - Mikulovskii, Iosif Stepanovich, 1950-64 (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - Morshen, Nikolai, 1955-62 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - "N" general, 1935-64, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 219-21)
    - Nabokova, Vera, 1954, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Narokov, Nikolai, 1948-64 (Box 10, Folder 223-26)
    - Navrotskii, IUrii Aleksandrovich, 1934-64, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1933-51, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 228-32)
    - Novoe russkoe slovo, 1948-64, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - "O" general, 1928-64, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 234-235)
    - Obolenskii, Sergei Sergeevich, 1936-53 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Obschestvo russkikh emigrantov "Kul'tura i progress" (Montevideo, Uruguay), 1949-51, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii, 1952-56, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna, 1953-64 (Box 10, Folder 239-42)
    - Ofrosimov, IUrii Viktorovich, 1946-64 (Box 10, Folder 243-48)
    - Ol'khovskii, Andrei Vasil'evich, 1952-54 (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - Ol'shanskii, Boris, 1949-56, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 250-51)
    - "P" general, 1931-65, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 252-57)
    - Pashin, Nikolai Sergeevich, 1953-54 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - Pasternak, Lidiia Sleiter
      See: Slater, Lydia Pasternak, Box 13, folder 322
    - Pavlikovskii, Mikhail Kazimirovich, 1947-64 (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Pavlov, Mikhail Ivanovich, 1948-59, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 260-61)
    - Petrov-Skitalets, Evgenii Stephanovich
      See: Step, Eugene S., Box 13, folder 331
    - Pletnev, R. (Rostislav), 1955-65 (Box 11, Folder 262-64)
    - Pogorelova, Bronislava Matveevna, 1953-63 (Box 11, Folder 265)
    - Pomerantsev, Kirill Dmitrievich, 1952-65 (Box 11, Folder 266)
    - Popel', Anton, 1949-50 (Box 11, Folder 267)
    - Popliuiko, Anatolii, 1948-51 (Box 11, Folder 268)
    - Pozdniakov, Vladimir Vasil'evich, 1948-54 (Box 11, Folder 269)
    - Pruzhan, David Veniaminovich, 1946-54 (Box 11, Folder 270)
    - Pugachëv, Kalistrat, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 271)
    - "R" general, 1936-64, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 272-79)
    - Rabinovich, IAkov Borisovich, 1938-63 (Box 12, Folder 280)
    - Raevskii, Vladimir Petrovich, 1946-51 (Box 12, Folder 281)
    - Rannit, Aleksis, 1957-65 (Box 12, Folder 282-85)
      See also: International P.E.N. Club. Series I, Box 5, folder 119
    - Reimers, Nikolai Aleksandrovich, 1952-62, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - Remizov, Aleksei, 1927-57 (Box 12, Folder 287-88)
    - Rossolimo, Kseniia Nikolaevna, 1950-51, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 289)
    - Rudneva, Vera Ivanovna, 1945, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Rudol'f, V.
      See: Shabinsky, Vladimir Rudolph, Box 28, folder 632
    - Rusanov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1948-49 (Box 12, Folder 291)
    - Russkaia mysl', 1947-64, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 292-93)
    - Rybinskii, Nikolai Zakharevich, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 294)
    - Rzhevskii, Leonid Denisovich, 1953-64 (Box 12, Folder 295)
    - "S" general, 1928-64, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 296-306)
    - Samoilenko, Grigorii Leont'evich, 1949-56 (Box 13, Folder 307)
    - Saninian, Suren, 1961-64 (Box 13, Folder 308)
    - Schatoff, Michael, 1949-51 (Box 13, Folder 309)
    - " Seiatel " (Buenos Aires)
      See: Cholovskii, Nikifor Avvakumovich, Box 3, folder 60
    - Semenov-Tian-Shanskii, Valerii Petrovich, 1963-64 (Box 13, Folder 310)
    - Sergeevskii, Anatolii, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 311)
    - Shatov, Mikhail Vasil'evich
      See: Schatoff, Michael, Box 13, folder 309
    - Shcheglov, Aleksandr Vladimirovich and Nina, 1949-59, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 312)
    - Sheroma, Vladimir Mikhailovich, 1950-59 (Box 13, Folder 313)
    - Shimaite, Annushka, 1948-64, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 314-15)
    - Shipman, Ol'ga and Leon, 1945-63, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 316-17)
    - Shor, Ol'ga Aleksandrovna, 1962-65 (Box 13, Folder 318)
    - Shtepa, Konstantin Feodos'evich, 1949-61 (Box 13, Folder 319-20)
    - Shub, David Natanovich, [1934]-65, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 321)
    - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1962-64 (Box 13, Folder 322)
    - Souvarine, Boris Konstantinovich, 1949-64 (Box 13, Folder 323)
    - Stankevich, Nataliia Vladimirovna, [1930]-64 (Box 13, Folder 324-25)
    - Stankevich, Vladimir Benediktovich, [1930]-60, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 326-30)
    - Step, Eugene S., 1959-65 (Box 13, Folder 331)
    - Stepun, Fedor Avgustovich, 1955-65 (Box 13, Folder 332-33)
    - Struve, Aleksei Petrovich, 1930-50 (Box 13, Folder 334)
    - Struve, Gleb, 1952-65 (Box 13, Folder 335-36)
    - "T" general [including Terapiano, IUrii Konstantinovich and Tolstaia, Aleksandra L'vovna], 1937-65, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 337-41)
    - Taube, Rudolf Evgen'evich, 1934-49, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 342-43)
    - Tauber, Ekaterina, 1952-64 (Box 14, Folder 344)
    - Tel'nov, IAkov Arkhipovich, 1949-58 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    - Timasheff, Nicholas Sergeyevich, 1952-64 (Box 14, Folder 346)
    - Timashev, N[ikolai Sergeevich]
      See: Timasheff, Nicholas Sergeyevich, Box 14, folder 346
    - Trubetskoi, IUrii, 1949-59, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 347)
    - TSeklinskaia, Irina Aleksandrovna, 1956-64 (Box 14, Folder 348-49)
    - TSetlina, Mariia Samoilovna, 1946-60 (Box 14, Folder 350)
    - TSurichenko, Aleksei Efimovich, 1949-64 (Box 14, Folder 351)
    - TSvetaeva, Marina, 1922-24 (Box 14, Folder 352)
    - Turoverov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1957-65 (Box 14, Folder 353)
    - "U" general, 1947-63 (Box 14, Folder 354)
    - Ul'ianov, N. (Nikolai), 1951-64, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 355-57)
    - "V" general, 1947-66, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 358-62)
    - Vasil'ev, Sergei Aleksandrovich, 1951-62, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 363)
    - Vedrov, Ivan Aleksandrovich, 1950-51 (Box 15, Folder 364)
    - Veidle, V., 1957-64, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 365)
      Includes letter by Wladimir Woytinsky, n.d.
    - Velichkovskii, Anatolii Evgen'evich, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 366)
    - Vendziagol'skii, Karol' Mikhialovich, 1961-65 (Box 15, Folder 367-68)
    - Vernadsky, George, 1959-64 (Box 15, Folder 369-70)
    - Vishniak, Mark Ven'iaminovich, 1939-59, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 371-72)
    - Vol'skaia, Valentina Nikolaevna, 1964-65 (Box 15, Folder 373)
    - Volskii, Nikolai Vladislavovich, 1945-61, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 374-81)
    - "W" general, 1937-61, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 382)
    - "Y" general, 1951-53 (Box 15, Folder 383)
    - Weinbaum, Mark Efrimovich
      See: Novoe russkoe slovo, Box 10, folder 283
    - "Z" general, 1946-63, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 384-86)
    - Zabezhinskii, Grigorii Borisovich, 1951-62 (Box 15, Folder 387)
    - Zaitsev, Boris, 1946-65 (Box 15, Folder 388-89)
    - Zamiatina, Liudmila Nikolaevna, 1949-64 (Box 15, Folder 390-91)
    - Zaretskii, Nikolai Vasil'evich, 1933-59, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 392-93)
    - Zavalishin, Viacheslav, 1950-[59], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 394)
    - Zeeler, Vladimir Feofilovich, 1948-54 (Box 16, Folder 395)
    - Zen'kovskii, Vasilii Valsi'evich, [1955-62], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 396)
    - Zenzinov, Vladimir Mikhailovich, 1920-51 (Box 16, Folder 397-98)
    - Zhabinskii, Vladimir Ivanovich
    - Zlobin, Vladimir, 1952-65 (Box 16, Folder 399-401)
    - Zurov, Leonid Fedorovich, 1955-65 (Box 16, Folder 402)
    - Unidentified, 1932-64, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 403-09)
  - OUTGOING
    - "A" general, 1945-65, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 410-11)
    - Adamovich, Georgii, 1955-65 (Box 18, Folder 412)
    - Aldanov, Mark Aleksandrovich, 1952-56 (Box 18, Folder 413)
    - Anin, David Sergeevich, 1961-65 (Box 18, Folder 414)
    - Annenkov, IUrii Pavlovich, 1956-65 (Box 18, Folder 415)
    - "B" general, 1933-64, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 416-18)
    - Berberova, Nina Nikolaevna, 1949-64 (Box 18, Folder 419)
    - Berezov, Rodion, 1952-63 (Box 18, Folder 420)
    - Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich, 1950-53 (Box 18, Folder 421)
    - Bunina, V. N. (Vera Nikolaevna), 1953-61 (Box 18, Folder 422)
    - Bychek, IAkov Konstantinovich, 1950-65 (Box 18, Folder 423)
    - "C" general, 1946-62, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 424-25)
    - Chinnov, Igor' Vladimirovich, 1953-65 (Box 18, Folder 426)
    - Cholovskii, Nikifor Avvakumovich, 1950-62 (Box 18, Folder 427)
    - Chyzhevs'kyi, Dmytro, 1952-65 (Box 18, Folder 428)
    - "D" general, 1948-64 (Box 18, Folder 429-31)
    - "E" general, 1935-64 (Box 18, Folder 432-33)
    - Editorial Planeta (Barcelona, Spain), 1955-62 (Box 18, Folder 434)
    - "F" general, 1949-62, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 435)
    - Fessenko, Andrew V. and Tatiana, [1951]-65 (Box 18, Folder 436)
    - "G" general, 1933-64, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 437-439)
    - Gazdanov, Gaito, 1960-65 (Box 19, Folder 440)
    - Glebov, Ivan Andreevich, 1959-63 (Box 19, Folder 441)
    - Golubowski, Aleksy, 1962-64 (Box 19, Folder 442)
    - Guzenko, Igor', 1954 (Box 19, Folder 443)
    - Gul', Ol'ga Sergeevna, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 444)
    - "H" general, 1948-64, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 445)
    - "I" general, 1947-65, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 446-47)
    - Il'in, Iosif Sergeevich, 1958-65 (Box 19, Folder 448)
    - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich and Ivanova, Irena Vladimirovna, 1953-55 (Box 19, Folder 449-50)
    - Ivask, George, 1953-65 (Box 19, Folder 451)
    - "J" general, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 452)
    - "K" general [including Kravchenko, Viktor Andreevich], 1946-65 n.d. (Box 19, Folder 453-56)
    - Kamkin, Viktor Petrovich, 1957-64 (Box 19, Folder 457)
    - Kanzaki, Naboru, 1959-63 (Box 19, Folder 458)
    - Karpovich, Michael, 1946-59 (Box 19, Folder 459-61)
    - Kerenskii, Aleksandr Fedorovich, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 462)
    - Khadzhiev, Razak Bek, Khan, 1953-63 (Box 20, Folder 463)
    - Khomiakov, Gennadii Andreevich, 1955-64 (Box 20, Folder 464)
    - Klenovskii, Dmitrii I., 1952-62 (Box 20, Folder 465)
    - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich, 1952-65 (Box 20, Folder 466)
    - Ktorova, Alla, 1960-64 (Box 20, Folder 467)
    - Kubanskii, Fedor, 1952-62 (Box 20, Folder 468)
    - Kurganov, Ivan Alekseevich, 1950-51 (Box 20, Folder 469)
    - Kuskova, Elaterina Dmitrievna, 1947-58 (Box 20, Folder 470)
    - "L" general, 1941-65 (Box 20, Folder 471-72)
    - Lazarevich, Ida Markovna, 1950-51 (Box 20, Folder 473)
    - "M" general, 1934-65, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 474-76)
    - Mackiewicz, Józef, 1961-64 (Box 20, Folder 477)
    - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich, 1953-55 (Box 20, Folder 478)
    - Margolin, IUlii, 1948-65 (Box 20, Folder 479)
    - Matskevich, Nikolai Emel'ianovich, 1953-55 (Box 20, Folder 480)
    - Mel'gunov, S. P. (Sergei Petrovich), 1948-51, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 481)
    - Morshen, Nikolai, 1952-63 (Box 20, Folder 482)
    - "N" general, 1934-64, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 483)
    - Narokov, Nikolai, 1952-63 (Box 20, Folder 484)
    - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1949-51, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 485)
    - Novoe russkoe slovo, 1952-63, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 486)
    - "O" general, 1948-64, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 487)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii, 1952-54 (Box 20, Folder 488)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna, 1953-64 (Box 20, Folder 489-90)
    - Ofrosimov, IUrii Viktorovich, 1954-62 (Box 21, Folder 491)
    - "P" general, 1937-64, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 492-95)
    - Pletnev, R. (Rostislav), 1955-65 (Box 21, Folder 496)
    - Pomerantsev, Kirill Dmitrievich, 1952-65 (Box 21, Folder 497)
    - "R" general, 1936-64, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 498-500)
      Includes letters by Vadim Viktorovich Rudnev and V. I. Rudneva
    - Rannit, Aleksis, 1957-65 (Box 21, Folder 501)
    - Russkaia mysl', 1949-64 (Box 21, Folder 502)
    - Rzhevskii, Leonid Denisovich, 1952-64 (Box 21, Folder 503)
    - "S" general, 1936-64, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 504-07)
    - Shor, Ol'ga Aleksandrovna, 1960-65 (Box 21, Folder 508)
    - Shub, David Natanovich, 1934-65 (Box 21, Folder 509)
    - Souvarine, Boris Konstantinovich, 1951-64 (Box 21, Folder 510)
    - Stankevich, Vladimnir Benediktovich, 1936-60, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 511)
    - Step, Eugene S., 1960-64 (Box 21, Folder 512)
    - Stepun, Fedor Avgustovich, 1955-65 (Box 21, Folder 513)
    - Struve, Gleb, 1952-65 (Box 21, Folder 514)
    - "T" general, 1935-64, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 515-16)
    - Tauber, Ekaterina, 1957-64 (Box 22, Folder 517)
    - Timasheff, Nicholas Sergeyevich, 1952-65 (Box 22, Folder 518)
    - TSeklinskaia, Irina Aleksandrovna, 1956-63 (Box 22, Folder 519)
    - Turoverov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1957-65 (Box 22, Folder 520)
    - "U" general, 1947-63 (Box 22, Folder 521)
    - Ul'ianov, N.(Nikolai), 1953-65 (Box 22, Folder 522)
    - "V" general, 1950-63, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 523-24)
    - Veidle, V., 1952-64 (Box 22, Folder 525)
    - Velichkovskii, Anatolii Evgen'evich, 1961-65 (Box 22, Folder 527)
    - Vernadsky, George, 1960-62 (Box 22, Folder 528)
    - Vishniak, Mark Ven'iaminovich, 1939-64, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 529)
    - Vol'skaia, Valentina Nikolaevna, 1964-65 (Box 22, Folder 530)
    - Vol'skii, Nikolai Vladislavovich, 1949-64, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 531-33)
    - "W" general, 1953-63 (Box 22, Folder 534)
    - Weinbaum, Mark Efimovich
      See: Novoe russkoe slovo, Box 10, folder 233
    - "Y" general, 1951, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 535)
    - "Z" general, 1950-64, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 536-37)
    - Zaitsev, Boris Konstantinovich, 1951-65 (Box 22, Folder 538)
    - Zamiatina, Liudmila Nikolaevna, 1952-64 (Box 22, Folder 539)
    - Zeeler, Vladimir Feofilovich, 1948-54 (Box 22, Folder 540)
    - Zen'kovskii, Vasilii Vasil'evich, 1951-61 (Box 22, Folder 541)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir, 1952-65 (Box 22, Folder 542)
    - Zurov, Leonid Fedorovich, 1955-65 (Box 22, Folder 543)
    - Unidentified, 1937-64, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 544-47)
  - THIRD PARTY
    - Karpovich, Michael (Box 24, Folder 548-51)
      - Incoming "Al-Zd", 1949-62, n.d.
      - Outgoing "E-V", 1952-58, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 552)
    - "A-Z" general, 1881-[1965?], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 553-73)
    - Unidentified, 1921-[65?], n.d. (Box 26, Folder 574-77)
- Writings, 1900-66; Series II; 9.25; (24 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is divided into four subseries. The writings to be published in Narodnaia Pravda (Boxes 28- 29) or Novyi Zhurnal (Boxes 30-47), Other Writings (Box 48), and Poetry (Boxes 49-50), all alphabetically arranged by author. Poetry of unidentified authors is located in Box 50, folders 1285-88.
  - NARODNAIA PRAVDA
    - Artem'ev, Viacheslav P. (Viacheslav Pavlich)
      - "Protest generala Buniachenko", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 578)
      - "Sovietskie propagandisty" (Box 27, Folder 579)
      - "Sovietskii plennyi", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 580)
    - Beloborodai, Georgii Gavrilovich: "Izviniaius' za gramotnost'... ", 1951 (Box 27, Folder 581)
    - Bukinik, Mikhail Evseevich: "Vo vremia Petliury... ", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 582)
    - Bychek, IAkov Konstantinovich: "Kto my, ili Nashe litso", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 583)
    - Del'vig, IA?: "Plan knigi", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 584)
    - Dmitrievich, M.: "Bor'ba za Rossiiu", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 585)
    - Donausov, ?: "M.A. Murav'ev", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 586)
    - Dostoevskaia, Ekaterina Petrovna: "O moem syne", 1948 (Box 27, Folder 587)
    - Dostoeyevsky, Fyodor: "Iz zapisei i prorochestv", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 588)
    - Dudin, Vladimir L'vovich: "Za kulisami voennoi strategii", 1950 (Box 27, Folder 589)
    - Emeri, Pavel
      - "O chem my sporim?", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 590)
      - "Peredavali... diskusiiu mezhdu... Stepunom i... Longom", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 591)
      - "V izdatel'stve 'Novyi put', n.d. (Box 27, Folder 592)
    - Fedorov, Nikolai Ivanovich: "Edinaia tsel'", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 593)
    - Fomin, Andreas: "Moe predskazanie", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 594)
    - G.K., G.R., S.M. [et al.]: "Protestuem", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 595)
    - Gerasimov, Dmitrii: "Puteshevstvie Ivana", [1950?] (Box 27, Folder 596)
    - Grishaev, ?; "Chiia vina?", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 597)
    - IAstrebov:
      - "Krestianstvo pri NEP", 1947 (Box 27, Folder 598)
      - Politika partii v osvobozhdennykh oblastiakh... v 1943 g.", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 599)
    - IAtsevich, Aleksei Viktorovich
      - "Mysli novogo emigranta", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 600)
      - "V liudiakh", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 601)
      - "Vrednyi konservatizm", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 602)
    - Kamskii, Dmitrii: "Ispoved' chekista", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 603)
    - Kerzhak, Vladimir: "Miagko posteleno", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 604)
    - Kodzhomberdiev, Kudaibergen: "O sovetskom Turkestane", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 605)
    - Kondrashov, V.: "Kak ia sluzhil v Soiuznom kontrol'nom sovete" (Box 27, Folder 606)
    - Kornosevich R. (Romual'd): "Uvazhaemyi g-n M.M. Karpovich; otkrytoe pis'mo", 1952 (Box 27, Folder 607)
    - Kraevskii, P.: "Dve Vinnitsy", 1950 (Box 27, Folder 608)
    - Kravchenko, Viktor Andreevich: "Rech... na sude" (Box 27, Folder 609)
    - Kubanskaia, V.: "Natsional'nyi vopros i demokraty", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 610)
    - L'vov, Lollii: "Sevlag i begstvo ottuda", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 611)
    - Makarov, ?: "Istoriia kochegara", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 612)
    - Mamchur, Andrei: "Pochemu ia ne vozvrashchaius' v SSSR", 1947 (Box 27, Folder 613)
    - Matveev, Leonid Alekseevich: "Istoriia naiznanku", [1951?] (Box 27, Folder 614)
    - Mikhailovich, Vladimir: "Otkrytoe pis'mo k rossiiskim emigrantam", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 615)
    - Narokov, Nikolai
      - "Chelovek drugoi porody", 1948 (Box 27, Folder 616)
      - "Protiv chego?", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 617)
      - "Sovetskii chelovek, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 618)
    - Natov, A.: "Krizisy ekonomiki SSSR", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 619)
    - Odinokov, N.G,: "Beshenstvo vlasti", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 620)
    - Ovodov, V.
      - "Izlishniaia otkrovenmost'", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 621)
      - "Radio, boty i potoka", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 622)
    - P.R.P.
      - "General'naia liniia", 1950 (Box 27, Folder 623)
      - "Pokozatel'nyi rastrel", 1950 (Box 27, Folder 624)
    - Pirogov, Petr Afanas'evich: "Na front", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 625)
    - Radojevich, M.: "Jedna... tragicna epoha", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 626)
    - Raevskii, A.: "Otkrytye karty", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 627)
    - Ratmirov, Igor': "Fragmenty iz knigi IA obviniaiu Kreml, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 628)
    - Rechberg, Arnold: "La première attaque bolchevique", 1946 (Box 28, Folder 629)
    - Reichardt, Waldemar: "Gutachten.. .", 1949 (Box 28, Folder 630)
    - Rogalia-Levitskii, IU: "Gore- ezhenedel'nik", [1950?] (Box 28, Folder 631)
    - Shabinsky, Vladimir Rudolph: "Sovetskii antisemitizm", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 632)
    - Sidorov, I.: "Utopischeskie plany", 1952 (Box 28, Folder 633)
    - Sofiev, Léo: "Pamiati uchitelia", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 634)
    - Stankevich, Vladimir Benediktovich: "[Aktsionernoe obshchestvo 'Zolotoi vek']; otryvok", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 635)
    - Tokaev, Grigorii Aleksandrovich
      - "Pamiati druga", 1951 (Box 28, Folder 636)
      - "Stalinskaia zabota o... aviatsii", [1952] (Box 28, Folder 637)
    - Trubetskoi, IUrii: "Ten' fiurera; fragmenty iz eppopei 'Puti krovavye'", 1945-47 (Box 28, Folder 638)
    - Tverskoi, Evgenii: "Shpion ponevole", 1949 (Box 28, Folder 639)
    - Vanovskii, Aleksandr; "Proroki sovremennykh bedstvii; Kukliarskii, Gogol' i Dostoevskii", 1950 (Box 28, Folder 640)
    - Vaulin, Vladimir
      See: P.R.P., Box 27, folder 623
    - Veresov, A.
      See: IAtsevich, Aleksei Viktorovich, Box 27, folder 600
    - Vladimirko, A.: "[Rossiia i Ukraina. K natsional'nomu voprosu]", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 641)
    - Volin
      - "Bumazhnye den'gi", 1946 (Box 28, Folder 642)
      - "Krestianskii vopros v osvobozhdennoi Rosii", 1949 (Box 28, Folder 643)
      - "Naivysshie dostizheniia kommunisticheskoi partii", 1946 (Box 28, Folder 644)
      - "Tupik", 1947 (Box 28, Folder 645)
    - Zavalishin, Viacheslav: "Vystrel, kotoryi opechalil stranu; k piatnadsatiletiiu so dnia ubiistva S. M. Kirova", [1948?] (Box 28, Folder 646)
    - Unknown and unidentified authors, 1946-49, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 647-70b)
  - NOVYI ZHURNAL
    - Akhmatova, Anna Andreevna: "Vospominiia [sic]. Poet Mikolai Stephanovich Gumilev", [1955?] (Box 30, Folder 671-72)
    - Akimov, A.: "Filosofiia russkoi istorii v khudozhestvennoi literature", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 673)
    - Alekseev, Nikolai Nikolaevich: "V burnye gody; vospominaniia", [1957?] (Box 30, Folder 674)
    - Alekseeva, Lidiia
      - "Elevator", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 675)
      - "Padenie Semena Semenovicha", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 676)
      - "Teddi iz Stokgol'ma", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 677)
    - Alekseevskii, Petr
      - "Gory i doly; roman." Part I, chapters 1-7, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 678-84)
      - "Minuvshie dni", [1953?] (Box 30, Folder 685)
    - Aleksinskaia, Tatiana Ivanovna: "Opal'nyi kniaz", [1954?] (Box 30, Folder 686)
    - Andrian, B.
      - "Obrechënnye; roman v stikhakh", 1952 (Box 30, Folder 687)
      - "Rasskaz gostia", 1952 (Box 30, Folder 688)
    - Annenkov, IUrii Pavlovich
      - "[Rvannaia epopiea]" Part I,II, chapters 1-4; 1 chapter, 1940, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 689-94)
      - "Tiazhesti; roman" Part I, chapter 1-6, 1940, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 695-700)
      - "Vsevolod Meierkhol'd", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 701-02)
    - Arbatov, Zinovii IUr'evich
      See also: Editorial Planeta, Box 18, folder 434
    - Arbatov, Zinovii IUr'evich: "Berlin", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 703-07)
    - Arbatsky, Yuri: "Poltora veka so dnia rozhdeniia Dargomyzhskogo", [1963] (Box 31, Folder 708)
    - Arsen'ev Nikolai Sergeevich (Box 31, Folder 709-10)
      - "[Chast' stat'i o kn.S.N. Trubetskom]", n.d.
      - "Iz letnikh vpechatlenii", n.d.